Kiss the rules goodbye.
Detroit Rock City is a comedy, music, adventure film directed by Adam Rifkin.
In 1978, a Kiss concert was an epoch-making event.
For the four teen fans in Detroit Rock City getting tickets to the
sold-out show becomes the focal point of their existence.
They'll do anything for tickets -- compete in a strip club's amateur-night
contest, take on religious protesters, even rob a convenience store!
Lex, played by Giuseppe Andrews.
Trip Hurudie, played by James DeBello.
Hawk, played by Edward Furlong.
Jeremiah 'Jam' Bruce, played by Sam Huntington.
Mrs. Bruce, played by Lin Shaye.
Beth Bumsteen, played by Melanie Lynskey.
Detroit Rock City is a 1999 American teen comedy film
directed by Adam Rifkin and written by Carl V.
It tells of four teenage boys in a Kiss tribute band who try to
see their idols in a concert in Detroit in 1978.
It took its title from the Kiss song of the same name.
The film stars Edward Furlong, Giuseppe Andrews, James DeBello, Sam Huntington, the members of Kiss
(Gene Simmons, Paul Stanley, Ace Frehley and Peter Criss), Natasha Lyonne and Lin Shaye.
The film was primarily shot in Canada, such as at Cedarbrae Collegiate Institute in Toronto and Copps
Coliseum in Hamilton, but also at Fox Theatre in Detroit, Michigan, United States.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
approximately $6 million against a $17 million budget.
It is a 1970s nostalgia film.
The film explores themes of parent child relationship,
1970s, kiss, drugs, detroit, michigan.
The tone is lighthearted.